<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../CBML_files/cbml.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:cbml="http://www.cbml.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sonic the Hedgehog #01</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>IDW Publishing</publisher>
            <pubPlace>U.S.A.</pubPlace>
            <date when="2018">April, 2018</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Retrieved from Grabber Zone
               (https://grabber.zone/comics/sonic-idw/2018-2019-neo-metal-sonic-saga/sonic-the-hedgehog-01/),
               an online Sonic comic collection gathered for educational purposes</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <tagsDecl>
            <namespace name="http://www.cbml.org/ns/1.0">
               <tagUsage gi="cbml:panel"/>
               <tagUsage gi="cbml:caption"/>
            </namespace>
         </tagsDecl>
         <p><note type="encoding_clarification">A value of 'NNC' for the cbml:panel element's
               @characters attribute is an acronym standing for No Named Characters, meaning no
               characters with names appeared in the panel.</note>
            <note type="encoding_clarification">A value of '???' for the cbml:balloon's @who element means that the speaker of the line is unknown or unclear for some reason. In certain scenes, the comic might be implying a line is said by one character, only to reveal it is someone else entirely.</note>
            <note type="encoding_clarification">A '(?)' within a note with a type value of
               'panelDesc' means that the encoding author saw something unidentifiable, or else is
               unsure of their own identification.</note>
            <note type="encoding_author">Encoded by Reece Cullen</note></p>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_01">
            <p rend="cornerBox"><desc>A small corner box at the top left of the comic
               cover.</desc>IDW <lb/>ISSUE <lb/>1 <lb/>COVER A</p>
            <p rend="title"><desc>The word 'Sonic' is in big gold and blue lettering, 'The Hedgehog'
                  is in white on a red backdrop</desc>SONIC<lb/>THE HEDGEHOG</p>
            <figure type="coverPage">
               <figDesc>Sonic is pictured in front of Green Hill Zone, with Tail flying behind him.
                  Sonic is posed with one leg forward and one arm crossed in front of him, holding
                  up one finger. Tails is gliding with his tails spinning and arms outstretched.
                  Small blue birds fly around the two of them.</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>SEGA</p>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_02">
            <figure type="render">
               <figDesc>A render of Sonic pointing forwards poking out of a red and blue star is centered on the page, framed with small golden rings</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p rend="credits">Written by Ian Flynn Pencils yb Tracy Yardley Inks by Jim Amash &amp; Bob Smith
            <lb/>Colors by Matt Herms Letters by Corey Breen
            <lb/>Edited by Joe Hughes &amp; David Mariotte Published by Greg Goldstein</p>
            <p>Special thanks to Anoulay Tsai, Mai Kiyotaki, Aaron Webber, Michael Cisneros,
               <lb/>Sandra Jp, and everyone at Sega for their invaluable assistance. For international rights, contact licensing@idwpublishing.com</p>
            <p>IDW<lb/>www.IDWPUBLISHING.com</p>
            <p>Greg Goldstein, President &amp; Publisher • Robbie Robbins, EVP &amp; Sr. Art Director • Matthew Rozicka, CPA, Chief Financial Officer • David Hedgecock,
               <lb/>Associate Publisher • Laurie Windrow, Sr. VP of Sales &amp; Merketing • Lorelei Bunjes, VP of Digital Services • Jerry Bennington, VP of New Product
               <lb/>Development • Eric Moss, Sr. Director, Licensing &amp; Business Development
               <lb/>Ted Adams, Founder &amp; CEO of IDW Media Holdings
            </p>
            <p>SEGA</p>
            <p>Facebook: facebook.com/idwpublishing • Twitter: @idwpublishing
            <lb/>YouTube: youtube.com/idwpublishiing Tumblr: tumblr.idwpublishing.com
            <lb/>Instagram:: instagram.com/idwpublishing
            <figure type="logo"><figDesc>Logos for FaceBook, Twitter, YouTube, Tumblr, and Instagram appear from left-to-right</figDesc></figure></p>
            <p>SONIC THE HEDGEHOG #1. APRIL 2018. FIRST PRINTING. © SEGA. Sega, the SEGA logo and SONIC THE HEDGEHOG are either registered trademarks or trademarks of SEGA Holdings Co., Ltd. or its affiliates. All rights reserved. SEGA
               <lb/>is registered in the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. All other trademarks, logos and copyrights are property of their respective owners. © 2018 Idea and Deign Works, LLC. All Rights Reserved. IDW Publishing, a division of Idea and
               <lb/>Design Works, LLC. Editorial officesL 2765 Truxton Road, San Diego, CA 92106. The IDW logo is registed in the U.S. Patend and Trademark Office. Any similarities to persons living or dead are purely coincidental. With the exception of
               <lb/>artwork used for review purposed, none of the contents of this publication may be reprinted without the permission of Idea and Design Works, LLC. Printed in Canada. IDW Publishing does not read or accept unsolicited submissions of
               <lb/>ideas, stories, or artwork.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_03">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="#sonic #narrator">
               <cbml:caption>Sonic the Hedgehog has spent years fighting the forces of Dr.
                  Eggman.</cbml:caption>
               <note type="panelDesc">Within the Final Egg, Sonic faces off with the Egg Viper, an
                  enormous serpentine robot piloted by Dr. Eggman.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="#sonic #narrator">
               <cbml:caption>Time and time again, the mad doctor attacks, Sonic strikes back, then
                  relaxes until Eggman returns.</cbml:caption>
               <note type="panelDesc">Atop the Final Forretress, Sonic battles the Egg Emperor, a
                  humanoide mecha equipped with a lance and shield.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#sonic #narrator">
               <cbml:caption>But after their last battle...</cbml:caption>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic stares down the Egg Dragoon, a flying robot with laser
                  wings and an imposing gatling gun arm.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="4" characters="#sonic #narrator">
               <cbml:caption>...Dr. Eggman vanished...</cbml:caption>
               <note type="panelDesc">Against an overcast sky, Sonic fights the Death Egg Robot, a
                  bulbous robot with a single glassy eye-like fixture and numerous tentacle
                  appendages.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="x" characters="#sonic">
               <note type="panelDesc">Within the gutters of the page's other panels, Sonic is framed
                  from the front, running forward with a determined look on his face.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_04">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="#narrator #sonic">
               <cbml:caption>...But his robot army did not!</cbml:caption>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Whuh-oh- That doesn't look
                  good.</cbml:balloon>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Sounds like the locals are putting up a
                  fight. I hope they don't mind me lending a hand!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Placing one hand on the ground, Sonic starts running in place,
                  his legs becoming a red blur.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#sonic">
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic speeds into the distance, leaving an elongated dust
                  cloud behind him. It's clear that the doors of the city have been blown wide
                  open.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_05">
            <cbml:panel n="1">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_a">Run! Get to the storm
                  bunker!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">A town resident holding a Cube Wispon distressedly directs
                  other unarmed residents away from approaching robots.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="NNC">
               <note type="panelDesc">The resident brandishes his weapon, shaking in fear. An Egg
                  Pawn looms closer.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="NNC">
               <sound>SOK</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">The Egg Pawn knocks the Cube Wispon out of the resident's
                  hands.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="4" characters="NNC">
               <note type="panelDesc">Numerous Egg Pawns approach the fallen resident, who cowers on
                  the ground.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="5" characters="#sonic">
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic appears as a blue blurring ball, bouncing between each
                  of the Egg Pawns and smashing them to pieces.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_06">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Hey! You hurt?</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_a">N-not really.
                  You're...You're <emph rendition="bold">Sonic!</emph></cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic extends a hand to the resident, picking up the Cube
                  Wispon too.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">The one and only. Here you go. Try swinging
                  it at the robots next time. I knew somebody who put it to good use.</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_a">N-not really.
                  You're...You're <emph rendition="bold">You're...<emph rendition="bold"
                     >THE</emph></emph> Sonic!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic hands the Wispon back to the resident, who stands
                  nervously.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Maybe get inside, buddy. Nice chat! Need to
                  save your town. Bye!</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_a">O-okay!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">The resident watches as Sonic dashes around a corner.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="4" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Sweet! The town militia! Bots coming in from
                  the north! You've got a guy holding his own out there!</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_militia_cat">O-okay! We're on
                  it!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic dashes past three armed animals, a cat, a dog (?) and a
                  rabbit, who appear worried.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_07">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="NNC">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_b">Hurry up! They're closing
                  in!</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_c">I'm trying! It's
                  stuck!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">A blue bird strugles to open a hatch on the ground while a red
                  fox (?) panics, watching a line of Motobugs drive closer.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="#sonic">
               <sound>WHOOSH</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic runs through the Motobugs, knocking them all
                  aside.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#sonic">
               <note type="panelDesc">As he skids to a stop, Sonic strikes a pose, winking and
                  flashing two finger guns. The residents stand in awe.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="4" characters="#sonic">
               <sound>FASSSH</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic dashes off the right side of the panel, throwing up dirt
                  behind him.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="5" characters="NNC">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_b">...All this terror might
                  be worth it if I get to say Sonic winked at me!</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#unnamed_vista_resident_c">I hope we survive long
                  enough to get his autograph!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">The residents, much calmer now, are very impressed by
                  Sonic.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_08">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="#sonic">
               <sound>WHAM</sound>
               <sound>REEEEEEEEEEEEEEEECH</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">An enormous hammerhead slams into the ground right in front of
                  Sonic, as he screeches to a stop, looking disappointed.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Oh hey, another hammer-guy. I liked the
                  earlier one better.</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic stands in front of an Egg Hammer, an imposing robot the
                  size of a building, with a hammer just as tall.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#sonic">
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic spin dashes into the Egg Hammer multiple times, forcing
                  him to step back. More Egg Hammers lurk behind the corner.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="4" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">Where ya goin'?</cbml:balloon>
               <sound>SMASH</sound>
               <note type="panelDesc">Jumping off of a window ledge, Sonic launches himself at the
                  Egg Hammer, who begins to raise their hammer.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_21">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="#sonic #tails">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">If you're so worried, you can always come with me.</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#tails">Yeah! Just like old times and-!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic and Tails' silouhettes are shown, Sonic's gesturing explainedly.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="#tails">
               <note type="panelDesc">Tails looks behind him, at the vista's destruction and two residents crying while holding each other.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#tails">
               <note type="panelDesc">Tails looks down, thinking to himself.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#tails">
               <note type="panelDesc">Tails closes his eyes and smiles, confident in himself.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="5" characters="#sonic #tails">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#tails">There's too many Badnik angs out there. You'll find them faster on your own.
               I'll stay here and help the locals rebuild their town.</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#sonic">You're a class act, buddy. We'll bash bots some other time.</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="#tails">Deal!</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic and Tails' silouhettes are shown, Sonic's gesturing explainedly.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_22">
            <cbml:panel n="1" characters="#sonic">
               <note type="panelDesc">As Sonic runs away from the vista, an Egg Flapper is seen hovering above.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="2" characters="NNC">
               <note type="panelDesc">In a close-up of the Flappers face, it's clear he's examining something closely.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="3" characters="#sonic">
               <cbml:caption type="speech" who="???" rend="blue text and balloon">"So...he survived the first trial. Unsurprising."</cbml:caption>
               <note type="panelDesc">Sonic is highlighted in a red crosshair, his picture being zoomed into focus.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="4" characters="#sonic #amy">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="???" rend="blue text and balloon">Deploy a battalion to the next nearest town. He'll be drawn to it like a moth to a flame.</cbml:balloon>
               <note type="panelDesc">A large chair is shown from behind, bearing Dr. Eggman's signature symbol. Sonic is being observed on the monitor in front of the chair. Amy is visible on another monitor to the left.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
            <cbml:panel n="5" characters="#sonic #amy">
               <cbml:balloon type="speech" who="???" rend="blue">Make sure word of Sonic's latest success reaches the Resistance. I want to crush <emph rend="bold">both</emph> headgehogs in one strike.</cbml:balloon>
               <cbml:caption type="teaser"><emph rend="blue geometric lettering">Next time:</emph> Can <emph rend="jagged lettering with red accents">LOVE</emph> hammer it out <emph rend="large geometric lettering">ON THE BATTLEFIELD?</emph></cbml:caption>
               <note type="panelDesc">A picture of Amy is shown zoomed in on a monitor.</note>
            </cbml:panel>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_23">
            <figure type="render"><figDesc>A render of Sonic standing and gesturing in a presenting fashion</figDesc></figure>
            <p><desc>Sonic is in blue and gold lettering, Letters Squad in white, all on a red backdrop</desc>Sonic Letters Squad</p>
            <p rend="blue text">Hello to all the Sonic fans new and old and welcome to the first issue of <emph rend="italic">Sonic the Hedgehog</emph> from IDW publishing! It's a monumental issue as your favorite blue blur and his best buddy Tails race into a new adventure... with the ever-capable Ian Flynn, Tracy Yardley, Jim Amash, Bob Smith, Matt Herms, and Corey Breeen bringing you our stellar first issue.
            But enought talk! Let's get to what you came here for. We asked and you delivered, so here are some fan letters nad the first batch of fan art!</p>
            <figure type="fanwork"><figDesc>Fanart of super sonic charging up an energy blast against a space backdrop.</figDesc></figure>
            <p>My boyfriend and I have been huge fans of Sonic since we were young! We collaborate on artwork often and this is one of our proudest creations, and would love to see it in print. an't wait to buy and read the comics!
            Lourdes M.</p>
            <figure type="fanwork"><figDesc>Fanart of Sonic, Shadow, and Rouge drawn in the style of the 80's cartoon</figDesc></figure>
            <p>Hi, Looking forward to the new series. I've attatched a piece of fan art I've done. Peace!
            Billy Kurtz</p>
            <p rend="blue text">This one's extra special as Billy's piece is the first one to arrive when the call went out on the IDW Sonic Comic Squad Facebook group!</p>
            <p>Good Evening, guys!
            I'm Rena Rose, I'm a cosplayer from Argentina! I belong to Sonic Team Argentina, one of the most important Argentinian pages reqarding Sonic news and content. Cosplaying Sonic characters is super FUN! I hope to cosplay more characters! I learned to sew 5 years ago to make my own costumes and I've won many cosplay</p>
         </div>
         <div type="page" xml:id="pg_24">
            <p>competitions in Argentina. My favrite character to cosplay is Amy Rose. She's so cool! &lt;3 I submited photos for publication. I'm looking forward to reading the new Sonic comics! Thank you for your tie.
            Best Wishes,
            Rena Rose</p>
            <figure type="fanwork"><figDesc>A picture of a woman is shown cosplaying Amy Rose, complete with a giant hammer.</figDesc></figure>
            <p rend="blue text">And Rena was the first cosplayer to send in some pictures!
            If you'd like your fanart, cosplay pictures, or letters to show up in this very space, send them to <emph rend="red text">letters@idwpublishing.com</emph>, include your name, and mark them "OKAY TO PRINT!" Also, don't forget to join the IDW Sonic Comics Squad Facebook roup to see even more amazing art and keep up-to-date with all the latest infor on your favorite comic! We'll see you back here with more letters and more fac art... NEXT WEEK?!? WHAT?!?
            -Joe Hughes and David Mariotte</p>
            <p rend="white text on red background">Top: Art by Chase Connolly.
            Bottom: Art by Abel Muniz, Jr.</p>
            <figure type="fanwork"><figDesc>A drawing of a robotic Big the Cat is displayed, with red eyes and sharp claws and ears. The picture is captioned: 'Metal Big the Cat!' and the robot has a balloon saying: 'Sonic and friends, I will conquer you and everything below the sun!'</figDesc></figure>
            <figure type="fanwork"><figDesc>Art of Sonic in his classic double finger-gun pose is shown, in a stylish matte-colored rendition.</figDesc></figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
